Guide to the Emil J. Dillon Papers, ca. 1873-1933
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - Subseries 1. Letters, Telegrams, and Related Notes
    - Greene, George A.1890 Dec. 14 - 1892 Sept. 23, Incl. a descriptive list, an offprint. (Box 15, Folder 30)
      Contains materials relating to Gie [Gei] [Gay], Nikolai Nikolaievich; Tolstoi. One material is in Russian.
    - Greville, Margaretn.d., Incl. a descriptive list, an offprint. (Box 15, Folder 31)
      Contains materials relating to Right Hon. William McEwan; Hon. Ronald Greville; George Keppel; Edward VII; Mewes; Davis; Osbert Sitwell; Beverley Nichols; Emerald Gunard; Mussolini; Lady Chamberlain; Mrs. Keppel; Harold Nicolson; Winston Churchill; Ribbentrop.
    - Greville, Sidney1917 [?] June 6, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Grey, Earl1914 Sept. 20 [?] (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Griffith-Blackler, W.F. [1 of 2]1906 July 24 - 1919 March 4, Incl. tls. (Box 15, Folder 34)
      Contains materials relating to President Wilson; Mr. Venizelos.
    - Griffith-Blackler, W.F. [2 of 2]1922 April 6 - Sept. 30, Incl. tls. (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Grigg, E.W.M. 1914 Sept. 23 - Sept. 26 [?] (Box 15, Folder 36)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Grey; Ramsey McDonald.
    - Grimthorpe, [?]1915 Feb. 6 - Sept. 27, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Grot, Konstantin Iakovlevich1912 April 23 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Grot, Konstantin Yakovlevich
    - Grove, Archibald1891 Oct. 21 - Dec. 26, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Guillard, Pierre1901 Jan. 20 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Gunzburg, Jaques, De, Baronn.d., Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Gutierrez [?], [?]1922 Nov. 10 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Guyot, Yves190 [?] Jan. 26 - 1901 July 30 [?] (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - H., J.1927 [n.d.] (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Hall, Frank1917 April 29 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Contains materials relating to Thomas & Henderson.
    - Hamilton, Ian1908 [n.d.] - 1918 [?] Jan 26; n.d., Incl. tls. (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Contains materials relating to Count Witte; Sir Rennell Rodd; Colonel Brooke; General Calwell; General Pau; Hanbury Williams; the Tsar; King George; Duke Nicholas; Lady Hamilton; Lady Essex; Mrs. Nora Lindsay.
    - Hammerton, J.A.1930 April 17, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Contains materials relating to Miss Furniss; Miss Alexander.
    - Hanotavx, S. [?]1911 May 3 - 1919 Feb. 14 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Harford, Frederic1890 August 16 / 28, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Contains materials relating to Aziz Bey.
    - Harlez, Charles, De [1 of 12]1879 March 27 - Dec. 13, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 13)
      Contains materials relating to Miehel-Anga [?]; Kossovich, K.A.; M. Ch. de la Vallée, Prof.; P. Van Beneden, Prof.; I. Pizzi, Prof.; Georg Curtius, Prof.; Ludwig Lange, Prof.; M.R. Pischel; Jacobi de Münster, Prof.; Patkanov, K.P.; Witting; M. Emil Joseph Michaelson; M. Bormans [?]; Theophilis; M. Alexandre Baschmakoff. Some materials are in French, Russian, and German.
    - Harlez, Charles, De [2 of 12]1880 Jan. 2 - Nov. 15, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [3 of 12]1880 Nov. 15 - Dec. [n.d.]; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [4 of 12]1881 Jan. 2 - August 24, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [5 of 12]1881 August 30 - Dec. 10, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [6 of 12]1882 Jan. 13 - Nov. 18, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [7 of 12]1883 Feb. 22 - July 26, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [8 of 12]1883 August 2 - Dec. 16, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [9 of 12]1884 Jan. 3 - Dec. 14, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [10 of 12]1885 Jan. 9 [?] - Dec. 15, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [11 of 12]1886 Jan. 23 - Dec. 6, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Harlez, Charles, De [12 of 12]1887 March 6 [?] - 1892 March 23 [?], Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, postcards, leaflets. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Frank [1 of 2]1890 June 7 - 1892 Sept. 6, Incl. press cuttings. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Contains materials relating to Mickiewicz, [Adam ?]; Kinloch Cooke; Heinemann; Tolstoi; Mr. Parnell; Batlesby [?]; Mr. Lanin; Ehlermann, D.E.; Weesner [?], J.A.; Hamilton, Gerald; Wilde, Oscar; Shaw, George Bernard. Some press cuttings are in Russian and German.
    - Harris, Frank [2 of 2]1930 June 29 - 1932 Jan. 31, Incl. press cuttings. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Harris, J. Rendell1898 Jan. 6 - March 28, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Contains materials relating to Ahikar; Dr. James; Harks [?]; W.M. [?].
    - Harrison, Austin F.1901 Nov. 4 - 1930 [?] Sept.; n.d., Incl. tls. (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Contains materials relating to Rasputin.
    - Hartry [?], Melville [?]1917 Oct. 22 - Dec. 24, Tls. (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Herschell; Major Vischer; Commander Taylor; Mrs. Dillon.
      Granville Baker [?]
    - Harvey, George, Colonel1905 [n.d.] - 1906 April 11, Incl. tls. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Contains materials relating to Phillips, Roland; Count Witte; the Tsar [Nikolai II].
    - Hausplant, Norman V.1921 Dec. 27 - 1922 March 16, Tls. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Contains materials relating to Robert Fleming, President; Mr. Kent; Mr. E.S.Busby; Mr. Luis Rubalcava; President Obregon.
    - Hayashi, Tadasu1905 June 27 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Contains materials relating to Prince Arisugawa.
    - Hehir, Dodo1930 April 23 - May 8, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      Contains materials relating to Konstantin Nabokoff; Mrs. Lasky.
    - Heinemann, William1890 Oct. [?] 21 - 1891 Feb. 12, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 17, Folder 12)
      Contains materials relating to Harris; Mr. John Cordy Jeaffreson; Byron; Shelley; Count Tolstoi; Professor Huxley; Mr. Gladstone.
    - Henry, Chas.1914 [?] April 19 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Henry, Meare [?]1919 June 4 [?], Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Herron, George D. [1 of 2]1919 March 5 - April 15, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 17, Folder 15)
      Contains materials relating to President Wilson; Balfour; Muehlon; Milner; Tompson; J.P. Morgan; Sir William Tyrrell; Mr. Paul Birukoff; Tolstoi; Count Sigray; Lammasch, Prof.; Lenin; Trotskii; Colonel House; Signor Sonnino; Prof. Foerster; Rasputin; Lloyd George; Count Montgelas; Prof. Nippold; Mrs. Herron. A press cutting is in French.
    - Herron, George D. [2 of 2]1919 April 23 - 1919 [?] June 15, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, typescripts, a press cutting. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Higgs, Mary Dominic, Sr.1910 Oct. 13 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Hillyard Alteridge, A.1905 Oct. 1 - 1917 Oct. 5, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Himma, Derwish1919 Feb. 4 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Hluela [?], [?]1903 Jan. 2, Incl. tls. (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Hodgkins [?], Jessie Marriott1918 May 29 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      Contains materials relating to Kirton Varley; Captain Spencer; the King of Albania; Beamish; Miss Tait; Mrs. [?] Gray [?].
    - Hogan, John, Father1888 May 21 - 1904 Jan. 22; n.y., Incl. tls. (Box 17, Folder 22)
      Contains materials relating to M. O'Reilly; John O'Mahony; Mrs. Pitt Byrne; Marbeau; M. Battersley [?]; Leo XIII; M. Vigouroux; Pére Granvelle [?]; H.H. Wyman C.S.P.
    - Hogan, J.F.1894 March 2 - April 15 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      Contains materials relating to Father Hogan; Mr. Harris.
    - Hoose [?], M., Colonel1918 Dec. 3 - 1919 March 21, Tls. (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Hovelague [?], E. [?]1919 Jan. [?] 21 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      Contains materials relating to Pailevé; Hubert [?] Munihoris [?]; Fuster; Albert Kahn.
    - Howard, Henry1891 [month ?] 18 / 30, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 17, Folder 26)
      Contains materials in French relating to Mr. & Mrs. Dillon; Battersby; Colonel Speranskii.
    - Hoyos, A., Count1912 Dec. 2 - 1922 Jan. 29 [?], Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 17, Folder 27)
      Contains materials relating to Sazonoff; King [of ?] Montenegro; Le Sage; Count Ijapary [?]; Mrs. DIllon.
    - Hubert-Valleroux, Leon Marie Emile1877 June 27, Incl. an obituary. (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Hughes, Wiiliam [1 of 2]1916 April 20 - June 12; n.d., Incl. tls, a typescript. (Box 17, Folder 29)
      Contains materials relating to Heith [?] A. Murdoch; M. Briand; M. Corrigan; H. Cordemay; Mr. Shepherd; Oliver E. Bodington; Mr. Fisher; Lady Northcote; Mr. Jonescu; Mrs. Elinor Glyn.
    - Hughes, Wiiliam [2 of 2]1916 June 13 - 1919 June 22, Incl. tls, a typescript. (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Hunt, W.P., Geo.1919 May 5, Tls. (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Huttey, [?]1928 Dec. 14, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 17, Folder 32)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Rotstein.
    - Hymans, [?]1919 June 8 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Ignatiev, V. [?], Count1895 July 21 / August 2 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Iliodor1922 Dec. 5, Incl. tls. (Box 17, Folder 35)
      Contains materials relating to Dr. George K. Pratt.
      Iliodore
    - Imperiali, N.Y. [?], Marchese1919 July 28, Incl. tls. (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Imperiale, N.Y. [?], Marchese
    - Inha, I.K. [?]1897 Sept. 19 - Nov. 15, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Ishikawa, Yasujiro1919 March 10, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Isidor, Metropolitan of St. Petersburg, Novgorod, and Finland1888 [n.d.] - 1938 May [n.d.]; n.d. (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Some letters are in Russian and German.
    - Islington, Anne1916 Jan. 25, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Izvolskii, A.P. [1 of 3]1906 Oct. 27 / Nov. 9 - 1908 Dec. 6, Incl. descriptive lists, tls, als, press cuttings, typescripts. (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Contains materials relating to S.M. L'Empereur François Joseph; Le Prince Ferdinand de Bulgarie; Obolenskii; President Lord Granville; Nicolas II; the Kaiser; Lobanoff-Rostoffskii; Prince Bülow; Lamsdorff; Lord Burnham; Curtis Brown; W.L. Lourtney; G.W. Prothero; Sir Nicolson; P.N. Miliukov; Poklevsky Kozell; Count Aehrenthal; M.Sazonoff; Lord Hardinge of Penshurst; Sir Edward Grey; Tittoni; General Dumbadze; Suvorin. Some materials are in French and Russian.
      Izvolsky, A.P.; Isvolsky, A.P.; Iswolsky, A.P.
    - Izvolskii, A.P. [2 of 3]1909 June 7 / 20 - 1918 April 21, Incl. descriptive lists, tls, als, press cuttings, typescripts. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Izvolskii, A.P. [3 of 3]1918 April 26 - 1919 May 25, Incl. descriptive lists, tls, als, press cuttings, typescripts. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Jakobi, M., Pastor1899 June 10, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Jameson, J. Eustace.1914 August 4 - 1917 May 4, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 18, Folder 10)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Frewen; Viscount Torrington; Mr. Ogilvie; Lady Torrington; Vera.
    - Joannides, Ange1911 Oct. 18 - Oct. 8 / 21, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Jones, Henry Arthurn.d. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Jonescu, Take [1 of 3]1894 June 6 - 1913 July 20, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 18, Folder 13)
      Contains materials relating to Chennadieff; Melinoff; M.Marghiloman, the Finance Minister; Mrs. Jonescu; King Ferdinand; King Carol; M.Maiorescu; Lucian Wolf; Tontsehff, the Bulgarian Delegate. Some documents are in French and Russian.
      Jonesco, Take
    - Jonescu, Take [2 of 3]1913 July 23 - 1914 March 31, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Jonescu, Take [3 of 3]1914 April 22 - 1919 June 6, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Jovino, F. [?]1885 Sept. 30 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      Contains materials in French and Russian relating to Mr. de Harlez.
    - Joyce, James1932 Oct. 30, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Kahn, A.W.n.d. (Box 18, Folder 18)
      Contains materials relating to Anousta Otto [?].
    - Kaldji, Charles A.1927 May 3 - July 30, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a postcard. (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Kalmykova, A.M. 1884 [n.d.], Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 20)
      The letter is in Russian.
    - Kaminski, Josef [1 of 2]1892 Nov. 30 - Dec. 30, Incl. a descriptive list, a postcard, press cuttings. (Box 18, Folder 21)
      Contains materials relating to Szczepanowski; Lobaczewski; Dr. Erazm. Some materials are in Russian, German, and Latin.
      Kaminsky, Ivan
    - Kaminski, Josef [2 of 2]1893 March 31 - Nov. [?], Incl. a descriptive list, a postcard, press cuttings. (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Kara-Georgevitch, Alexei and Daria1917 Jan. [?] 1, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Keppel, George[n.y.] Feb. 22 - Oct. 23, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Key, Helmer, Fil. Dr.n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 25)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Wallenberg, the Foreign Minister.
    - Khoruzhii, M.1917 April 27 (Box 18, Folder 26)
      Contains materials in Russian relating to B.Rewlin; L. Rodstein.
    - Kidston, George1912 July 10, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - King, Norman1908 June 6 / 19 - 1921 Sept. 6, Incl. tls. (Box 18, Folder 28)
      Contains materials relating to M. Stolypin; H. King, Esq.
    - Kingston, Beatty1897 Feb. 1 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Kirpichnikoff, A.I. [1 of 2]1886 July 1 - 1914 April 30 / May 13; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, postcards. (Box 18, Folder 30)
      Contains materials relating to E. Garshin; Rikker; Olenina; A. Potebnia; Stasov; Shiller; Lomnitskii; Nekrasov; Saburov; Minaev; Uspenskii; Demianov. The letters and postcards are in Russain.
    - Kirpichnikoff, A.I. [2 of 2]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, postcards. (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Knobel, F.M.n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Knorring, [?]n.d. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Knörring, [?]
    - Kohanik, Peter, Rev.1918 Nov. 4, Tls. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Kokovtseff, W., Count1912 Jan. 17 - 1917 [?]; some dates are unreadable., Incl. a descriptive list, a typescript, tls. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Some materials are in Russian and French.
      Kokovzoff, W., Count; Kokofftseff, W., Count
    - Konitza, Mehmed1913 August 6, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Konovalov, S.1859 [?] Feb. 3 - Feb. 16, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Konried, Julius1897 Jan. 19 - 1915 April 7 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Two letters are in German.
    - Korostovich, I.n.d. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Contains correspondence in Russian relating to S.Iu. Witte, Count.
    - Kossovich, K.1878 Oct. 1 - 1880 August 15 / 27 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      Contains correspondence in Russian relating to Prof. S.I. Kossovich; Prof. Knaap; Prof. Arle; Vasiliev.
    - Kovalev, Maxim1909 June 9 [?] (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Kroeger, Otto G.1922 Jan. 30 - June 14, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Contains materials in German relating to Herr kolb-Danvin; Herr Edmund Stinnes; Herr Korff.
    - Kurz, Elie [?]1908 Feb. 24, Incl. a descriptive list, als. (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Kurtz, Elie [?]
    - Kutschena, M.1894 June 5, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Kyhlberger, G.A.1917 Jan. 4, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Lampritis, Th. [?]1903 Jan. [?] 18 / 31, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Landon, Peveral1919 [n.d.], Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Lansbury, George1919 June 30, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Lansdowne, [?], Lord1918 March 27 - May 15, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 18)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Milner; Moreton Frewen.
    - Lara, Isidore, De1917 Oct. 29 - 1927 Dec. 23, Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting, tls. (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Contains materials relating to Alice De Monako, La Princesse.
    - Lawley, Francis1894 Jan. 26 - Feb. 2, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Lawrence, F.W.1903 Jan. [?] 10 - 1931 July 7, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Contains materials relating to Mrs. Pethick-Lawrence.
      Pethick-Lawrence, F.W.
    - Leather, Fitzherbert1914 Nov. 20, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 22)
      Contains materials relating to Lord Leighton; Thomas Cutler.
    - Lecco, D.M.1914 Nov. 20, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, an offprint. (Box 19, Folder 23)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Stepan Raditch. One material is in Croatian [?].
    - Leckie, C.S.1902 Oct. 22 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Lenutz [?], Blanche [?]1914 Oct. 16 - 1915 Dec. 25, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Leo XIII, Pope [1 of 2]1899 Jan. 1; n.d., Incl. offprints. (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Leo XIII, Pope [2 of 2]1902 March 12, Incl. offprints. (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - LeRoy Lewis, H., Colonel1916 Feb. 10 - 1919 Jan. 27, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 28)
      Contains materials relating to Captain Baring.
    - Lerroux y Garcia, Alejandro1914 [n.d.] - 1924 April 26, Incl. tls, a typescript, a postcard. (Box 19, Folder 29)
      Contains materials relating to Garcia Prieto; Maura; Ventoza; Rodes. Some materials are in Spanish.
    - Leskov, Nikolai Semenovich [1 of 3]1891 Dec. 3 - 1893 Feb. 10 / 22; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, typescripts, a postcard. (Box 19, Folder 30)
      Contains materials relating to Leo Tolstoi; Alexander III, Emperor; Countess A.A. Tolstaia; Hugh McLean; Father Ioann of Kronstadt; Mr. Constantine DIllon. Some materials are in Russian.
    - Leskov, Nikolai Semenovich [2 of 3]1952 Oct. 20 - 1954 [n.d.]; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, typescripts, a postcard. (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Leskov, Nikolai Semenovich [3 of 3]n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, typescripts, a postcard. (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Levashoff, V.V., Count1891 July 18 - 1899 Oct. 29; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, postcards. (Box 19, Folder 33)
      Contains materials relating to Princess Wiasemsky; Countess Levaschoff; Nelidoff. Some materials are in French and German.
      Levaschoff, V.V., Count; Levachoff, V.V., Count
    - Leveson-Gower, G.G., Esq. [1 of 2]1904 April 28 - Dec. 8, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 34)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Harry Lawson; Mr. Lavino; Mr. Harvey; Napoleon III; Baron Gravenitze; Mr. Spring-Rice; Mr. Austin Harrison; Count von Bülow; Plehve; the Kaiser; the Tsar; Lord Cowper; Colonel Haig.
    - Leveson-Gower, G.G., Esq. [2 of 2]1904 Dec. 29 - 1932 Sept. 11, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Liliental, Erich1922 March 14, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Lisle, Edwin, De1891 April 20 - 1901 May 6, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Litvinov, Ivy1928 Dec. 10 [?], Incl. a postcard. (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Locock, Guy1916 April 12, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 39)
      Contains materilas relating to Mr. Khylberger; Messrs. Rowe.
    - Lodge, H.C.1918 Oct. 19, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 19, Folder 40)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Frewen.
    - Loisy, Abbé Alfred, Dr. [1 of 3]1896 July 26 - 1930 Nov. 14; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, typescripts, an offprint. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Some materials are in French and German.
    - Loisy, Abbé Alfred, Dr. [2 of 3]1903 March [n.d.] - 1931 Sept. [n.d.], Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, typescripts, an offprint. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Loisy, Abbé Alfred, Dr. [3 of 3]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, typescripts, an offprint. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Louis, Jaques[n.y.] July 14 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Löwenstein, Prince, Von[n.y.] May 16, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Luzatti, [?]The date is illegible. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Lynch, George[n.y.] June 13, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Lynch, H.F.B., M.P.1904 June 25, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - MacDonald, Ramsay1924 Sept. 8 - 1925 July 14, Incl. tls, als [?]. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      Contains materials relating to General P. Elias Calles; President Elect.
    - Mahabharati, Alokananda1921 Dec. 15, Incl. tls. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Makino, N., Baronn.d. (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Maliarevskii, A.n.d. (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Mallet, Louis, Sir [1 of 2]1906 Feb. 26 - 1917 Sept. 12; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, tls. (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Contains materials relating to Enver; Djemal; H.M.G.; Said Halim.
    - Mallet, Louis, Sir [2 of 2]1917 Sept. 17 - 1945 [?] Oct. 27, Incl. a descriptive list, typescripts, tls. (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Manheim, Louis, Dr.1919 July 13, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 20, Folder 15)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. W.G. Middleton Edwards.
    - Manuel II, King of Portugal [1 of 2]1917 July 8 - 1918 Jan. 16, Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting, tls. (Box 20, Folder 16)
      Some materials are in Spanish.
    - Manuel II, King of Portugal [2 of 2]1918 Feb. 3 - 1932 July 22, Incl. a descriptive list, a press cutting, tls. (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Marchenko, M.1891 [?] March 15 / April 2 [?] - 1894 May 21 / June 1, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Marlborough, Duchen [?]1925 [?] [n.d.] (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Martinengo, Evelyn1919 March 21 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Matsuoka, Yosuke [?]1919 April 2 - 1933 March 15, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 20, Folder 21)
      Contains materials relating to Mrs. Dillon.
    - Mavrodiu, C.D.1917 April 18, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Mavromikhalis, K.P. [?]1909 [?] - 1911 March 24; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 23)
      Mavromichalis, K.P. [?]
    - Maximoff, J.1923 March 16 - 1927 Dec. 14; n.d., Incl. postcards. (Box 20, Folder 24)
      Contains materials relating to Mrs. T.G. Bewley; Mr. George Dobson; Mr. Constantine Dillon. One letter is in Russian.
    - Max Muller, W.G.1916 Oct. 24, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Maxse, J.L., Esq.1904 Nov. 30 - 1909 May 20, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, als [?]. (Box 20, Folder 26)
      Contains materials relating to the Tsar; Julius; Mr. Meredith; the German Emperor; Sienkiewicz; Baron Kikuchi; Delcassé; Clemenceau; Maxwell L. [?].
    - Mayer, Charles [?], Judge1918 Nov. 11 - 19 [19 / 20 ?] [n.d], Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 20, Folder 27)
      Contains materials relating to Drzewiecki, Pres. of the City of Warsaw; Rabbi Wise Paderewski; Dmowski; Captain Mayer.
    - McClure, S.S.1890 August 26 - 1919 Dec. 12, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 20, Folder 28)
      Contains materials relating to Count Tolstoi; Mr. Verschoyle; Mr. Heinemann; George Kibbe Turner; Harriet H. McClure.
    - McCormack, John, Count1938 [?] Dec. 22 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - McGarry, Rutledge [?], W.M.1921 July 29, Incl. a descriptive list, tls. (Box 20, Folder 30)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Albert B. Kingsberry; Northclif; the King; Lloyd George; Curson; Pinero; Liebnitz; Kolchak; Wrangle; Famine; Milesius; Carlotta; Mrs. McGarry.
    - Mee, Arthur1908 July 29 [?] (Box 20, Folder 31)